focusfanatics.com 2014-12-18

# Ford Focus Forum, Focus ST Forum, Focus RS Forum - PrivacyPolicy

**The Focus Fanatics Privacy Policy**  
Focus Fanatics is committed to protecting your privacy. To make your online experience more convenient, we gather information from you. We maintain the privacy of your information using security technologies and adhere to policies that prevent unauthorized use of your personal information. 

**What information does Focus Fanatics collect and how is it used?**  
We might request additional information from you in the future. You may choose not to provide this information; although, some products and services might not be available to you unless you provide the additional information. We might also ask for information about your interests or for feedback about our site so that we can tailor your visit to improve our site and service. Providing us with this information is always optional.

When you submit a supporters review, we ask for your email address so other supporters have additional information about who wrote the review. You can choose not to have your email address display with your review.

In addition to the information we collect directly from you, we also monitor and track usage of our website, viewing and traffic patterns, supporters behavior, and other similar information. We compile this information into a statistical aggregate. We use this aggregate information as well as all of your personal information for internal business and administrative purposes including to improve our website, our product and service offerings, our operations, and our supporters service. We also might use your personal information from time to time to send you notices about special offers, new products, services, promotions, and other similar information. 

**About IP Addresses**  
Focus Fanatics collects IP addresses when submitting posts to the bulletin board and for the purposes of system administration. An IP address is a number that's automatically assigned to your computer whenever you're connected to a network or connected to the Internet. When guests request pages from Focus Fanatics, our web servers log the guests' IP addresses. We do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable. This means that a user's session will be logged, but the user remains anonymous to us unless issues of security arise in which IP addresses may be turned over to local, state and national authorities.

**Use of Cookies - The Focus Fanatics Cookies Policy**  
What are cookies? Cookies are pieces of information that a Web site transfers to an individual's hard drive for record keeping purposes. Cookies make Web-surfing easier for you by saving your passwords, purchases, and preferences while you're at our site. The use of cookies is an Industry standard, and you'll find cookies at most major Web sites.

**Examples of How Focus Fanatics Uses Cookies**  
The Focus Fanatics bulletin board uses cookies to store the following information: the last time you logged in, your username and password, and your preferred "topic view", if you set it in preferences. These cookies are stored on your browser. Cookies are not used to track your movement or perform any function other than to enhance your use of the bulletin board. If your browser does not support cookies, or you have not enabled cookies on your browser, many of these timesaving features will not work properly. Also, you need to have cookies enabled in your browser if you want to enter a private forum. Focus Fanatics. also uses cookies to let the computer remember that you've registered, which allows us to speed up your future activities at our sites.

**How Focus Fanatics Does Not Use Cookies**  
Focus Fanatics never uses cookies to retrieve information from your computer that was not originally sent in a cookie. Except as described below, Focus Fanatics. does not use information transferred through cookies for any promotional or marketing purposes, nor is that information shared with any third parties whatsoever.

**Links to Other Sites**  
Users should be aware that when you are on the Focus Fanatics web site you could be directed to other sites that are beyond our control. There are links to other sites from Focus Fanatics that take you outside our service. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, the "click" takes you off the Focus Fanatics site. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and partners that may use Focus Fanatics's logo as part of a co-branding agreement. These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data or solicit personal information. Always be aware of where you end up. Please keep in mind that whenever you give out personal information online - for example, via message boards or chat - that information can be collected and used by people you don't know. While Focus Fanatics strives to protect its user's personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose online and you do so at your own risk.

**Security Policy**  
The importance of security for all personally identifiable information associated with our Guests is of utmost concern to us. We exercise great care in providing secure transmission of your information from your PC to our servers, utilizing encryption software. Only those employees who need access to your information in order to do their jobs are allowed access, each having signed compressive nondisclosure agreements, which provides explicit legal confidentiality protections. Any employee who violates our privacy and/or security policies is subject to disciplinary action, including possible termination and civil and/or criminal prosecution.

**Your Acceptance of These Terms**  
By using this site, you signify your assent to the Focus Fanatics Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our site. Your continued use of the Focus Fanatics site following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. You can send an e-mail to **[info@focusfanatics.com](mailto:info@focusfanatics.com)** with any further questions.
